gentlemen a very warm welcome to ICICI
Lumber General Insurance Company Limited
Q2 and H1 f523 earnings conference call
from the Senior Management we have with
us today Mr bhargav Das Gupta MD and CEO
of the company
Mr gopal balajandran CFO and cro
Mr Sanjeev mandri executive director
and Mr alak Agarwal executive director
please note that any statements comments
are made in today's call that may look
like forward-looking statements are
based on information presently available
to the management
and do not constitute an indication of
any future performance as future
involved risk and uncertainties which
could cause results to defer materially
from the current views being expressed
as a reminder
all participant lines will be in the
lesson only mode and there will be an
opportunity for you to ask questions
after the presentation concludes
should you need assistance during the
conference call please signal an
operator by pressing star then zero on
your Touchstone phone
please note that this conference is
being recorded
and I'll hand the conference over to Mr
bhargav Das Gupta mdn CEO ICICI Lombard
General Insurance Limited thank you and
over to you sir
thank you and uh good evening to each
one of you uh thank you for joining the
earnings conference call of ikc number
General Insurance Company Limited for
the second quarter and the half year of
fi 23.
I will give you a brief overview of the
industry Trends and developments that we
are we have witnessed in the last few
months post this RCA phones will share
the financial performance of the company
for a quarter and half year ended
September 30 2022.
domestically the economic activity has
been Gathering fees and the recovery is
evidenced by the The High Frequency
indicators in the industrial and the
services sector
the Improvement in consumption spending
is expected to be sustained by strong
festive demand and possible Improvement
in rural consumption in the second half
of the year
the systemic credit is quite robust and
broad-based
at the same time head will stop
geopolitical tensions tightening Global
Financial conditions strong dollar and
elevated Global inflation is slowing
Global demand resulting into lower
Imports which may have an adverse impact
on economic Indian economic growth in
the near term
the new vehicle sales with this strong
growth for Private Car segment and it's
easing supply chain constraints and
festive demand
the commercial vehicle segment grew
robustly supported by online demand
while the two wheeler segment continue
to remains low compared to the three
pandemic levels
health insurance continually drives the
overall industry growth
the commercial lines witnessed growth in
line with the current market environment
we remain optimistic that the industry
will continue to grow given the lower
Insurance penetration positive consumer
sentiment and enhanced risk awareness
as a result the GI industry delivered a
gdpi growth of 15.3 for the first half
of this year over the first half of last
year
excluding crop insurance this growth uh
is at 18 for the same period
however we continue to see pricing
regression in certain segments like
motor while there is some improvement in
group health segments for motor business
combined ratio for the industry was
124.5 in order one of Wi-Fi 283 as
compared to 107.1 for quarter one of
fy22 as for public disclosures
overall the combined ratio of the
industry improved from 11
111.4 in quarter one of 2023 as compared
to 124.0 in quarter one of 2022.
in the recent past the authority has
announced several reforms to increase in
Insurance penetration in the country
during the quarter The Authority has
issued and proposed following changes
one the exposure draft for an extensive
management and payment of commission
regulations proposing an aggregate limit
at a company level
to master guidelines on AML including
kyc requirements along with establishing
internal policies procedures controls
and compliance Arrangements effective
November 1st 2022
number three increase in the number of
triumphs from three to nine in case of
corporate agents for each category of
insurance
number four other forms of capital
wherein insurers can raise Capital by
way of reference shares or supported in
debt without having to Avail prior
approval of the Authority number five
amendments to the regulatory sandbox the
canvas regulations eliminating time
limit to facilitate innovation in
products or Solutions
and to increase the experimental period
up to 36 months these are all under
consideration and we believe that these
and many other changes have been made or
are being proposed which will have a
significant positive effect on product
Innovation ease of doing business and
insurance penetration
moving to business impact for us during
the quarter the company grew by 22.6
degree growth of 15.6
coming to the growth of key segments
during the quarter
we remain focused on growing our market
share in certain key profitable sub
segments within motor overall new
vehicle sales have been strong and
demand sentiment also continues to be
positive
we are optimistic that will be improving
pricing environment we will be able to
consolidate leadership position given
our strength of distribution in the
segment
our investment in detail has the
solution resulted in growth of 15.8
percent as against eight point zero
percent quarter one of five by twenty
three within the quarter we have
outgrown the industry and Standalone
players for the month of September with
the growth of 21.1 this was given by
growth of business forced by legal
health agency vertical of 30.7 in the
quarter two of fi 23.
I would also like to share that our
One-Stop One-Stop solution for all
insurance and wellness needs I'll take
care of has surpassed 2.7 million user
downloads till date the incremental
download for the quarter was 1 billion
our bank issuance and key relationship
uh grew at 36.1 percent this quarter
within this its a Bank distribution grew
at 33.9 and non-ic Bank distribution
grew by 37.6 percent
post pandemic the recovery in credit
along with the increase in volunteer and
distribution Partners acquired through
the demerger has been the growth driver
our business source through our digital
one team grew by 24.5 percent
overall our digital Focus has enabled us
to increase our digital revenues from to
uh 2.26 billion rupees which have also
for about 4.4 percent of our overall
gbpa for the quarter
as well as far as the commercial lines
are concerned we experience Rover's
growth driven by 26.9 growth in the SMA
segment
we remain on track and are focused on
growth levels such as launching new
products strengthening our distribution
engine digital enhancements realizing
Synergy rationalizing cost wise carrying
up our preferred lines of business I
will now request gopal to take you
through the financial numbers for the
Recently concluded quarter
good evening to each one of you I will
now give you a brief overview of the
financial performance of the company for
Quarter Two and hu and FY 2023
the results presentations are already
put up on the stock exchanges and we are
in the process of putting up putting it
on the website of the company you can
access it as we walk you through the
performance number
the gross direct premium income of the
country
is 105
billion in H1 f523 as against rupees
86.13 billion H1 fy22 a growth of 22.6
percent
this growth was higher than the industry
growth of 15.3 percent GDP was at rupees
51.85 billion in q23 as against rupees
44.24 billion due to FY 22. the growth
of 17.2 percent this growth was higher
than the district growth of 10 percent
growth of spring was primarily driven by
growth in preferred segments the overall
GDP of Property and Casualty segment
grew by 16 at rupees 32.13 billion in H1
f523 as against rupees 27.69 billion in
H1 f522
on the retail side of the business the
GDP of the motor segment was at rupees
37.09 billion in H1 F by 23. as the
gained should be 32.46 billion in H1
f522 registering a closer 14.3 percent
our agents which included which include
the point of sale count for the first
time crossed one lakh to one lakh 636 as
on September 30 to 2022 from 94 559 as
on June 30 2022
excluding the impact of cyclone and
flood losses of rupees 0.28 billion the
combined ratio was 104.2 in H1 fy23 as
against 113 in H1 FY 22 excluding the
impact of cyclone and flood losses off
which is 0.82 billion
combination was 105.1 percent in Q2 FY
23 as against hundred and five point
three percent in Q to fy22 excluding the
impact of Blood and Cyclone losses of
rupees 0.28 billion the combined ratio
of 104.3 percent in Q2 F by 23 as
against 103.7 in Q2 fy22 excludes that
again excludes the impact of
cyclone and fat losses of 50.5 million
our investment ethics Rose to rupees
400.96 billion as a September 1322 from
the investment leverage rate of
borrowings was 4.08 times
on a quarterly basis investment income
increased to rupees 7.39 billion in
q2f523 as against would be 7.16 billion
in Q2 f522 investment income of quarter
2523 includes impairment on Equity
investment assets of rupees 0.89 billion
as per the company policy
our capital gain net of impairment on
Equity investment assets stood at rupees
1.43 billion in H1 fy23 as compared to
rupees 4.71 billion in H1 F by 22.
capital gains net of impairment on
Equity investment Assets in Quarter Two
FY 23 was lower at rupees 1.11 billion
as compared to rupees 1.44 billion in
quarter to fy22
our profit before tax grew by 26.1
percent that rupees 10.75 billion in H1
f523 as against rupees 8.52 billion in
H1 fy22
whereas profit before tax grew by 2.7 it
would be 6.1 billion in 42.523 as
against rupees 5.9 billion nine four
billion in q2f522
consequently profit after that grew by
46.6 at RS 9.40 billion in H1 f523 as
against six point four one billion h1f
by 22. whereas profit after taxes at 2
by 32.2 percent that increase 5.91
billion in Q2 f523 from
rupees 4.47 billion in quarter to fy22
profit after tax for tutor 523 includes
reversal of tax provision of rupees 1.28
billion excluding this growth in profit
after tax was 26.5 and 3.4 for H1 and Q
at 523 respectively
return on average Equity was 19.9 in H1
f523 has against 15.2 percent in H1 f522
the return on equity for for quarter to
fy23 was 24.5 percent as against 21 in
quarter to f522 excluding the reversal
of tax provision the return on average
equity for H1 and q2523 was at 17.3 and
19.3 respectively
so obviously ratio was at 2.47 times as
at September 3022 as the case 2.61 times
less than June 30 22 continued to be
higher than the regulatory minimum of
1.5 times
the board of directors of the company
has declared interim dividend of rupees
4.5 percent for H1 FY 22 degree
the company has exercised a call option
to redeem the debentures of rupees 2.20
billion in full along with the final
interest due course received of
necessary regulatory or statutory
approvals on June July 7 2022 the record
date for the same was office 7 2022 thus
the outstanding debentures tanks that
rupees 0.35 billion as at September 30
2022 as I conclude I would like to
reiterate we continue to stay focused on
profitable growth sustainable valuation
and safety interest of quality holders
at all times
I would like to thank you for attending
this earnings call and will be happy to
take any questions that you may have
thank you
thank you very much sir
we will now begin the question and
answer session
anyone who wishes to ask a question may
press star and one on your Touchstone
telephone
if you wish to remove yourself from the
question queue you may press star and
two
seconds are requested to use handsets
while asking a question
ladies and gentlemen we will wait for a
moment while the question queue
assembles
myself
the first question is from the line of
swarna Mukherjee from bnk Securities
please go ahead
yeah hi thank you for the opportunity
sir
I have three questions first of all uh
the flow through from gross written
premium to mechanic premium so I can see
that there have been a sequentially
higher retention level during the
quarter
and also since there is some unexpired
risk reservatives that has happened if
you could highlight what explains this
that would be my first question second
is of the motor book so the gdpi mix
shows that there is a higher share of
private Vehicles again
um if you could throw some light up what
is going on there and what is the reason
behind the DP loss ratio the outcomes
ratio and thirdly uh on the crop crop
portfolio so we have reached at 800
crore kind of a number in first half I
think you had mentioned earlier that you
want the Run rate of what RTX used to do
in crops so does that mean that there
would not be any sort of a premium
inflows in crop uh going ahead in the
second half so these are the three
questions
uh thank you let me take the third
question and I'll ask to answer the
first and we will jointly give you
handle the second
um on the crop business it's a seasonal
uh you know mix uh is usually bigger and
the point that we had made earlier was
that compasses will remain about five
five plus minus five percent of our of
our portfolio I don't think there's
going to be any change in that so second
half of the year the amount of
properties will be significantly lower
than this number that you see in the
first half again the principle that we
are following is the business that came
from baji which had a Serial commitment
that we are maintaining
and apart from that the new business
that we've written is largely on the or
entirely on the 1810 model certain
States as you know have shifted to 1810
model where the cost of reinsurance for
us is significantly lower because of the
natural limit of loss at 110. so that's
what we have written but the mix of the
business will be uh you know will be
much more in the first half compared to
the second half overall guidance that we
had given in terms of composition of the
mixer portfolio that doesn't change
I think there are a couple of elements
in there one is sequentially why is the
retention uh ratio higher uh so if you
look at I think uh quarter one typically
is a period of commercial policy renewal
where the extent of reinsurance support
are relatively higher and that's the
reason why you find quarter one
detergent ratios to be relatively lower
than Q2 Q2 is more a book where you also
get to see the highest proportion of
retail business coming through and hence
to that extent sequentially is why you
find the retention ratios for Quarter
Two to be higher than quarter one
otherwise in that sense there is is
largely to do with the kind of distress
mix that we have for Q2 relative to Q
uh to your second point on uh in terms
of our next flight risk Reserve releases
being slightly elevated I think that's
primarily again a function of so again
no change in the way we kind of earn
revenues it's over the period of the
contract as one of your questions was in
the context of crop booking given the
fact that Curry's season typically has a
shorter time cycle when it comes to
earning of revenues and as to that
extent you will obviously find an
elevated levels of earnings coming
through in Quarter Two having said that
obviously you also kind of given the
fact in line with what you explained in
so far as the loss experiences are
concerned unless and until we don't have
the complete estimate of the claims
experience till that point of time we
obviously continue to provide for losses
at hundred percent of the earnings that
has happened so that's primarily the
reason why you get to see uh slightly
elevated earnings as compared to let's
say maybe the relative period that
you're looking at uh on the motor uh let
me maybe take it uh you know the mix of
the business is in line with what we had
indicated at the beginning of the year
and I mean the last conference call
uh you know I don't know where you've
got this point about private car
increasing actually it's coming down if
you look at last year first half private
car was about 56.5 percent of our mix as
we speak for this year first half uh
56.5 percent this year is about 49.6 the
increase is largely in TV uh two minutes
similar for almost 30 26.5 has gone to
27.1 and CV has increased from 17.1
percent to 23.4 percent in line with
what we had been saying for the last
couple of quarters TV mix will be you
know in the mid-20s range so given the
loss dynamics that we are seeing in the
private car particularly a particularly
private car motor OD is We Believe
significantly uh underpriced at this
point in time we've been a bit more
cautious on the private car segment and
any case as part of our stability of
increasing our very selected TV business
that that strapping is paying out and if
you see the growth of TV we have a very
good goal for the first half the CV
business has gone on about 56 percent
for us this first half
so just to follow up on that uh
very quick
yeah so uh actually uh in terms of the
myths I was talking about what had
happened sequently so in q1 I think the
previous was
47.7 and uh in the first time it was
49.6 so from that point of view I was
asking whether you know you were seeing
most reactions
so if you look at last year Q2 we had
about 57 of weeks coming from private
card this year is 51 percent in spite of
the time that we uh festive season has
been at least threefold so foreign
basis
okay so I've got it thank you thank you
sir uh that's all from my side
thank you thank you the next question is
from the lineup price Jain from motilal
oswal please go ahead
yeah hi hi everyone uh just a few
questions from my side first is on the
health claims Health claim ratio they
have increased significantly on a
sequential basis uh so could you break
it down as to what was the reason uh
secondly uh could you throw some light
on the implementation of vehicles act
and how how is it standing out across
the country and do we see some benefits
of it coming down coming in the news in
in the next couple of quarters or it's a
more driven from from an active
perspective how do we see that happening
and lastly uh the should you decide the
reason for the dip insolvency or no uh
on a sequential basis that would be good
so maybe let me take this last part
first the decline in the solvency is
purely a function of what kind of growth
rate that you seek and the mix of
business that you write
um so as I said I think Quarter Two
generally tends to be a portfolio mix
which is relatively more also in favor
of retail and as per the current Factor
based solvency regulations that are in
place the relative Capital requirement
for a retail business is far higher than
electricity commercial line of
businesses so hence that's purely a
function of what kind of business
volumes that you write but otherwise if
you see I think we are quite comfortable
with the level of solvency that we are
operating at which is about
2.47 times the second element what you
also look at uh in terms of impact on
solvency I think this is something that
you will get to see more or less in
every quarter too is uh post I mean we
declare dividends so for a final
different declarations happen towards
the end of the year which gets confirmed
that the AGM and the payment happens in
quarter two so that action there is also
an outflow on account of dividend
payouts which tends to have an impact in
so far as solvency numbers are concerned
so otherwise it's a minor sequential
decline but these are the two key
factors is with respect to solvency
outcomes to your first point on the loss
ratio numbers I think when you look at
health for example the breakup for the
Lost ratios for the corporate books I am
giving you quarter two numbers quarter
to FY 23 numbers the corporate or let's
say the employer employers loss ratios
are about 99.1 percent and the retail
Indemnity numbers and that
broadly the kind of uh range that we
have spoken about on the corporate
Hillside and our details has Indemnity I
think the loss ratios for Quarter Two is
at about 64.4 percent
sequential increase in the loss ratios
can be attributable to what factors
because uh the intensity or is it
Monsoon related or uh what what would be
the factors about dry driving a increase
in sequentially
so there are some seasonality impact of
uh you know Monsoon and uh you know
medical attitude cases you know the the
Dengue malaria and also there's usually
a spike that we always see in this
period
um so and the second point of a
sequential is that the previous quarter
there could have been some releases that
we got in that water uh but overall the
number is not going to be as high as as
the number that gopal talked about for
the whole year our senses that group and
this is a group of the entire employee
not the uh B2B to see the bank of
business is separate but the group
employment my last ratio will remain in
the uh you know ballpark number that we
had indicated which is you know in the
mid 90s for the year as a whole what we
will also see is that uh even as we
speak on a on a base if you remember
last time we used to talk about the fact
that we had asked for we had gone back
to our clan you know corporate plants
and taken price increases uh female per
Life had increased post covet uh and we
you know this year also on top of that
we are seeing some price increases so we
are quite comfortable with the group
health portfolio as we see it you know
just one quarter numbers may not be
fully reflected with the book that we
are writing
your last point on motor third party
again you know there are some early
signs but it's too early for us to call
uh you know we would want to watch this
for a couple of quarters before we take
a final view on whether the motor
vehicle acts in PK impact is uh Across
the Nation we are seeing some early
signs here and there but that's not uh
it's too early for us to take a call
that it's a uh it's happened at a
national scale
thank you thank you so much
thank you the next question is from the
line of Shreya Shivani from clsa please
go ahead
uh so I have two questions uh first is
on the
overall growth uh I wanted your opinion
on uh
how should we sorry how should we build
further
given up you guys have grown at 23 and
particularly your health book I mean on
month-on-one basis you guys are writing
400 crores uh that way so I want to
understand how sustainable this 23 is or
particularly the group sorry the health
uh book of 400 crores per month is first
is on that second I wanted to understand
maybe a little bit better Insight on why
is there so much uh cyclicality or
movement in your uh investment yields
between one q and 2q like the quarterly
move is quite high if I see it over
previous years the quarters of previous
years it wasn't this um this wide so I
wanted to understand that as well
is running on the first one uh clearly
the growth momentum uh is higher than
what we anticipated our integral at the
beginning of the year in the first half
if you see uh we've been uh
significantly more careful about the
private car business in spite of that
we've been able to deliver the growth
numbers that you are seeing
so my sense is that the health numbers
are sustainable uh you know the point
that we've been making with the
investment that we've made on the agency
distribution we are beginning to see
that uh play through enthusias as we
mentioned in our opening remarks the
agency retail health agency numbers are
picking up
Group Health we are seeing some
improvement in pricing uh some of the
large players who've been in the past
very aggressive they are toning down
their aggression on pricing and getting
a bit more discipline so even on a group
as an employer employee portfolio we are
seeing uh conversions at prices that we
we are comfortable with so I don't see
any constraint at the last thing on the
on the health side ICC bank has
restarted Distributing the indemnity
policy on the on the uh you know on the
on the home home site so that's why the
bank numbers are high and and the banker
overall numbers are also high for given
the tires that we got through the
acquisition they are performing really
well and the credit uh you know
dispersals are higher so our attachment
businesses are also picked up so on the
health side we even reasonably
optimistic and confident about
maintaining uh you know outperformance
and growth water actually you know as I
said you know Market has been over
aggressive and I don't believe it's
sustainable we are again seeing some
players uh retalibrate on the CV side uh
further as in reduced discounts and you
know improve increased prices uh we want
to see we are seeing quite a few players
taking similar decisions the Private Car
Side equally there are a few players who
are still aggressive so if pricing
aggression gets muted on the motor side
it may give us an opportunity to go even
faster than what we've grown in the in
this quarter that you know again We're
Gonna Be watchful but I don't see the
numbers going below the current those
numbers that you're seeing so overall we
remain reasonably confident about the
growth
you know trajectory that you said I
think the only you know concern that we
you know remain uh in about the market
is the pricing on the motor on that
website something that you would want to
watch
a bit closely
I think story is purely a function of
what kind of uh interested environment
that you see in the market I think at
this point of time we are seeing an
increasing interest rate regime and
therefore to that extent you will
obviously find the used to kind of
fluctuate between uh periods uh so
otherwise it's purely a function of what
kind of mix of investment that we are
making and largely to do with the
interest rate environment that's uh
operating so that actually you will
always find uh cyclicality in terms of
outcome so that's one and secondly when
you look at the overall yield on the
aggregate assuming on the entire
investment income when you look at
obviously it's a function of both inters
acros as well as capital gains and you
will never find uh evening of capital
gains uh across periods for example if
you look at let's say the happier
numbers the capital gains for let's say
first half is just about 1.43 billion
this uh this half year this number when
you look at H1 of the previous series at
about 471 crores so when you look at the
yield on the overall portfolio including
the on a realized basis and you will
obviously find fluctuating outcomes
but look at it from an overall
in so far as our interest accruals are
concerned because typically when you
look at our overall investment income
breakdown on an average it roughly about
70 to 75 percent of our investment
income is through accruals and typically
on an average balance 25 to 30 percent
is capital gains
and within quarters obviously there can
be cyclicality with respect to what the
actual yields are foreign
thank you
all right thanks for the opportunities
actually uh what is the number of number
on the sales that we have done from the
ieltic here as you shared that number
last quarter what is the number uh that
we have achieved this for that secondly
the downloads that we have done which
have been done in on the healthy caref
has been quite uh strong this quarter so
how are we driving that downloads are we
uh you know are we incurring any cost to
to to to make a customer download this
app and then second question third is uh
your commentary on the on the
competitive intensity that few players
have become are recalibrating that is on
motor TP or modern 4D segment uh uh that
you are seeing uh reduction in computer
intensity and if and what are your sense
that in by what time period we may start
seeing uh motor on damage competent
density coming down
given that it has been quite intense for
the last couple of years and lastly is
there any comment on them and the on the
management succession planning given
that there is a possibility of cap on
CEO 10 years of 15 years these are the
three questions
and then we get the last one out uh you
know the yes the exposure draft is there
for 15 years uh it's an explosive draft
if it becomes a final regulation then
obviously something will have to be done
uh but we will wait for that exposure
that to uh come true
the second question on aggression we are
as we mentioned see the real problem is
in the OD segment I mean you know we uh
in opening remarks we talked about the
overall combined ratio for motor the
combination for motor only is even worse
than that so TP is actually proven to be
better at this point in time
um so the aggression is in certain
segments and aggression gets played out
in terms of since you can't do anything
with the ticket price people you know
kind of uh do higher discounting in the
OD or income higher cost in uh in
getting that business so the problem is
more in the OD side
the other question that you had on I'll
take care just to give you uh the uh so
one is the you know how we write having
it what we're doing is you know
initially if you remember I'll take care
app was largely set up to
you know engage our corporate customers
what I mean by corporate customers is
the employees of corporate customers so
when we sell our group health insurance
policy it's a policy sold to a corporate
but the health insurance is for the
employees and really there was hardly
any engagement with them so that was the
original uh you know uh thought process
where we launched it about a bit more
than two years back
as we speak today more than 50 percent
of the employees of our corporates have
downloaded the app and use that app uh
and that for this percentage has been
increasing quarter and quarter so that's
one
area where how we how we prevent this
the second is you know gradually we now
you know putting a lot of effort on the
uh on the bank insurance and the agency
and the retail side and there you know
it is not as easy to you know bring
about change users as a behavior shift
and you know you're working with
Distributors and agents Etc but even
there we are seeing very good traction
uh largely because people are seeing
value in that engagement so so overall
there is you know there may be some cost
per is called material but overall we
are driving it through uh basically
conversion you think about it we have
roughly a lasting we had about 30
million policies that we sold right so
uh you know let's say 2.7 million
download still gives us a lot of
randomized growth uh you know a lot of
those numbers may be small ticket or uh
two wheeler policies but still we see
that as an opportunity so that's what
we're driving your last question on on
sales
so here's this is something that we
started only last year so it's beginning
to pick up and when we talk about sales
it's uh you know it includes the
renewals that people do on their own on
the app that number in q1 was about 9.8
crores that number is uh grown roughly
three times in this quarter so it's
become a 27.4 curves for this water and
for the month of September September it
was about 10 crores so we are seeing
very very good question in terms
in terms of even in terms of the you
know the working track monthly average
users daily average users
those numbers
so we are seeing very good traction with
that app as originally as we had talked
about this being a potential game
changer for us engagement models with
customers foreign
so going forward this will be the
basically and it will continue to
increase right is that that's the right
understanding
very difficult to comment on that
details because we will have to wait and
see in terms of how the how does the
interest rate cycle play out as I kind
of mentioned an increasing interest rate
regime obviously offers well for us in
so for us infrastructures are concerned
but equally you should be mindful of the
fact that correspondingly to that extent
aftermarket specifically on the 16th
book you will obviously have a master
Market negative and therefore the
ability of us to possibly realize any
amount of capital gain you may not see
that happening so when I kind of wave
that broad split of Lexis 77 interest
approvals and 25 30 view of capital K
that could possibly see some kind of a
change but if this momentum of let's say
interested cycle sustains then from an
overall as close continue to accrue from
business realization which will
definitely help in overall uh increase
in the yield of the boat yeah so maybe
your point is right I mean the carry
deal should keep on increasing given the
yeah it's very positive from a longer
term perspective
but on a quarterly basis the point that
gopal is making on capital gains that
makes layout uh you know opposite to
that positivity
trying to understand the adjusted for
capital gains there is no one option the
accrual yields because accrual leads in
last two quarters have increased quite
significantly almost 130 basis point
while our tenure of the book is four
years and we were of the opinion that it
will improve but it will improve solely
but it has improved quite significantly
in those two partners so I was trying to
understand there is no one-off in the
accrual means
foreign
Capital please go ahead
74.3 in the current quarter uh is it
just because of the price discounting or
or to some extent we can believe is it
is it true that the the new policies
that is pay as you go and and the other
policies which which industry has
introduced uh has has also contributed
to the loss issues and if you believe
this pay actually goes kind of a
policies are going to increase in the
contribution
are we seeing structurally higher loss
ratios in Motorola business going ahead
so the answer to your first question is
no because the contribution of those
policies is uh negligible as we speak so
that is I'm going to move the needle not
just now for a long period of time in
our estimate uh the second part of a
question in the long term what will it
do look logically what it should do
we'll have to wait to see what happens
is the price risk more granularly for
better customers so if a better customer
get a cheaper price logically The
Logical customer should pay a higher
price now whether the second thing will
happen or not that time will tell but
that is how it should play out it should
you know give us more uh ability to
price a propane I mean in the past we've
done done secondary measures of driving
behavior right LCB and you know what not
this gives you ability to price based on
driving behavior and driving distance so
you should price uh your risk better
doesn't mean that it should overall
become cheaper for the whole category
okay got itself and and second um see
the personal accent cover of business
which is highly profitable has seen a
very strong growth when I look at one
age and second quarter number which is
even getting reflected in the uh uh uh
uh so in the banker Channel numbers what
you have mentioned is it just wanted to
understand so that this these numbers
are sustainable Beyond fi23 because
because these channels initially started
started doing business for us and and
therefore this delivered the growth and
and they just wanted to know the
sustainability of these particular
numbers that even given it has been very
strong
q1 in the first
question we had a base effect of the
previousclass water right uh you know
that was the second uh the Delta wave
and the you know the business samples
were very very low uh last year first
quarter so on that beat the first
quarter of this year looks very very
elevated so the percentage it may not
sustain but in the absolute terms yes we
will be optimistic benefits
okay so and finally a fundamental
question if I look at a historical trend
for the industry as a whole uh the area
growth of the industry or or even for
your company is always being higher
compared to gdpi growth but but if you
look at the current year Trend it it is
almost the opposite because GT value
growth is very strong but but a young
growth somehow is struggling
so so because it's just eight percent of
on year on year breaches uh for our
company
just wanted to understand uh uh what
what is that Missing Link which is not
driving the alien growth uh uh compared
to what we have witnessed in the past
again is a function of uh let's say uh
what kind of business outcomes are you
operating at now at this point of time
forget as you have as you would have
seen and what we have been talking
through is that in so far as our
combined ratios are concerned I think it
is currently slightly at elevated levels
than what we would expect it to operate
at so for example you saw the numbers
for Q2 at 305 905.1 half here was reach
104.6 so hence that direction obviously
the relative acquisition to cash flows
or electricity asset Center management
will be relatively lower so that's uh
one component that will be a function of
what you say relative to growth second
when you specifically look at in the
context of quarter two you will always
find the flows to the overall assessment
management to be lower that primarily it
happens because as I mentioned in
response to one of the earlier questions
q1 is a period where you see bulk bulk
of the corporate renewals taking place
where you end up getting the premiums in
quarter one however given that where I
mentioned also that the corporate book
generally tends to have higher
proportion of reinsurance as per the
reinsurance arrangements those
settlements takes place in quarter two
so bulk of the outflows again happen in
Q2 and hence that accent and not just
this quarter two if you look at
historically in any of the water tones
you will find relatively the flows that
get approved in so far as the overall
investment book is concerned to be lower
so end hence as we kind of continue to
improve in bringing down the overall
combined ratios within acceptable
threshold over the next couple of years
is what we have indicated you should
logically get to see a higher proportion
of of float getting approved in the
investment book so that's the second
component the third in line with what we
have indicated I think relative to again
what kind of business mix that you write
for example health as we indicated will
not have as much of a long tail of
clothes compared to let's say motor and
at this point of time I think insofar as
the motor Hook is concerned given the
relative competitive intensity that we
see in the market we are a bit cautious
our health is doing reasonably well for
us and hence that's also a function of
what kind of
foreign
before we take the next question a
reminder to the participants please
limit your questions to do for
participant for any follow-up may be
requested to rejoin the queue
the next question is from the line of
neeraj toshniwal from UBS India please
go ahead
uh numbers uh wanted to understand the
tonight I think there have been some
questions
and that is impacting or I want to read
about it
yes as as I mentioned uh you know we are
seeing some green shoots in CV we are
seeing some moderation from some other
you know some of the larger uh
traditional players
um in 4D we are seeing some of the
players now rationalize the aggression
however at the same time there are still
a few players who are very aggressive
our sense is that this will not sustain
but you know that is the reason why
we've been saying that we are a bit
cautious in the own damage segment
think about it
so it's really the trend that we've been
talking about for last
in a couple of years there's been
aggression but it's sustained I mean
generally as you know I think we've
mentioned this many times but generally
we see this admission tone down after
about a year and a half this time it
just came probably because of the Copic
benefits that people saw last year we
were probably expecting this to come
down you know like moderate sooner this
year it's taking a bit more time but
early signs are uh early signs are you
know quite quite better you know early
signs are positive so we are optimistic
with a second half will be uh a bit
better than what we've seen in the first
time
also in terms of Premium so how how
actually uh overall given the commercial
that's already doing well and this
already picked up in his uh what kind of
growth are we tenders internally uh
I think I answered that question earlier
you know my our sense is that visually
what we indicated in the beginning of
the year we're given the optimistic that
we had
foreign
thank you the next question is from the
line of Avinash Singh from MK Global
please go ahead
yeah a couple of questions uh first uh
if I look at the overall you know
commercial lines particularly you know
uh the library that is quite profitable
but you will have you seem to have lost
markets here so either Market has gone
too fast and you have been cautious so
what is driving sort of your markets are
lost in that highly profitable line that
particular liability uh so that's one
and second uh would be more on what is
uh I mean again the media reporting
around this uh B Master completely uh
considering that is in more targeting uh
health professional retail of one hour
how do you see some kind of a channel
conflict there to be elevation
so Avinash in terms of liability uh last
year there was launch of a product by
one company last year which
you know is classified as a liability
program which The Authority has now uh
asked the industry not to write so if
you look at our group uh as it is our
growth you know for uh for Q2 is roughly
about 36.4 percent so our business
continues to do well uh into the market
share it is only because of that you
know that one company is one product
which we believe right now is not there
in the market that's the that's the
reason that you are seeing market share
jobs but the traditional Library
business which is profitable the one
that you're talking about that's
something that we continue to do well
and we are going and behaving number one
in uh you know in traditional liability
uh if you keep out this HCL browser
you're talking about uh your second
question was we didn't get your second
question Avinash we can just repeat your
second one yes it's around bhima sugam
that uh you know the direct distribution
initiative that uh for media report has
only come uh so will there be a channel
conflict because I mean this is I will
try to reach uh you know retail
customers retail health is something
where you or anyone else Drive business
a lot through agency so will there be
some kind of a channel conflict because
I mean you need to have differential
pricing otherwise I mean just give us to
them is kind of a you know obtained from
data that they want
so our senses that this will be this is
something that the authority is also
very keen on so this will uh you know
pick up and take up and our senses are
it will actually increase the
penetration rather than creating Channel
conflict uh we will have to wait to see
what the governance of that entity you
know the understanding that we have at
this point in time is that it will be a
industry control control density as if
the shareholding will be largely
distributed across the players with
maybe a technology partner who will also
have you know some some State we will
have to design the governance mechanism
of that entity and the products that go
on there we will have to see what goes
there and you know which which segment
of customers it focuses on overall we
believe it's a it's a great positive in
terms of uh creating greater awareness
because everyone will talk about it and
the fact that if something that the
regulator is endorsing it should create
the fair approach to Distribution on on
life that we've been kind of hoping for
and waiting for so we are quite
optimistic about this
okay on motor TV losses so there are
three moving parts of course you have
seen three four percent Blended price
high or maybe in the CV maybe higher
second part of course you have you know
uh this motor vehicle act implementation
that probably is kind of a religious
fraud and all and third part only of
course and that is typically doubled you
can come you know already very extreme
or details as well so all they should
put together you sort of for your friend
for the first half see that you are
still seeing uh you know a lot of
improvement or scope for improvement
because ultimately at this point
estimation and you have been typically
very very conservative what makes you
feel sort of all that okay the motor TV
with these three moving Parts is going
to improve
was that the question
yeah so I'm saying the price hike had
happened but it's muted but claim
inflation are very very strong I mean in
a motor TV particularly some extreme
clean Awards and then uh of course motor
vehicle act will have positive impact so
there are multiple moving Parts but if I
see uh you know your motor TP kind of a
claims ratio for first half there is a
movement uh so I mean because I mean my
clients uh yeah so my case is typically
doubled it close to double a so what is
a sort of for your view I mean you are
facing this uh to go down
but it's better to look at analysis
66.6 uh to give you a sense of what we
believe is a more you know reasonable
accessible number having said that I
think the point that you're making in
terms of uh claim inflation you know
this is the point that we've always been
making and accordingly we've had
reasonably High claim inflation numbers
in our reserving
we believe that a lot of companies hold
uh you know significantly lower
percentage of inflation and you know in
a sense that may be inadequate
um but we are quite comfortable with the
inflation number that we are holding
what we want to observe is the frequency
drops that we anticipate because of uh
because of the uh the the new motor
vehicle act that we you know earlier
responded to but the frequency drop you
have to watch for before we conclude
that it's actually come through and you
know the reduction is for ETC that
you're talking about is coming through
my sense is that we'll give it some time
to to develop for us to build confidence
and talk about a reduced number uh I
know that explains you what are the
short term uh thinking is and what we
believe can happen in the long term
thank you
the next question is from the line of
anjuman Dev from icaca Securities please
go ahead
yeah hi good evening and thank you for
the opportunity
my question was regarding the comment
that you made on the ICC Bank restarting
uh some of the attachment sales for a
home alone so is this the uh the kind of
benefit products that uh you know we
used to sell earlier because that was
very profitable and used to contribute a
decent amount to our Prospect if you
could clarify on that thank you so
anchovan I mentioned that it's an
Indemnity product and it's not just this
quarter even last quarter we had
indicated that the bank had we started
selling attachment of Health integrity
uh so that's where the growth is very
strong uh obviously the product concept
is very different from the original
benefit construct and accordingly
profitable profitability will be very
different
thanks or not that's it we are thank you
thank you
the next question is from the lineup
Deepika Mundra from JP Morgan please go
ahead
um
thank you thanks sir for taking my
question so just following up on the
ICICI Bank uh a loan link product in
terms of scale is there scope to go back
to the earlier scale of premiums that
were being done even so it's an
Indemnity product
look at an aggregate relationship with
the bank there are many things that we
do right it's not it's not one product
that we sell with the bank so there is
uh SME business that we do with them
there is the corporate business that we
would do with them there is help
business across different lines be it
attachment or in terms of Indemnity that
we do with them
uh in aggregate the relationship is
becoming has become bigger uh the reason
why we want to talk
was because this last year was a a bit
of a drag because the health business
the fashion business has been stopped
the point that we are making is that the
attachment business has started though
the product construct is different from
what it was last year
the prior to last year
I understood so answers are on the
retail Health the portion uh could you
tell us a little bit about the
experience on renewals that are coming
in from the older books so what would be
the renewal rate of uh older customers
uh and uh in terms of loss experience
between new and old customers what would
be the differential
so you asked a question about what can
we go back just to give you a sense of
the numbers we aggregate uh ICC Bank
contribution if you go to two years back
before they took that call was about 5.9
last year dropped over 5.3 percent even
though that big business which we
Associated attachment went away we build
other we do other uh other segments
other categories for q1 this year sorry
Q2 this is week on over 6.1 percent so
so in a sense for the half year we are
back to a similar number that we had in
2021 in terms of her contribution now
obviously our business has grown so I
think the bank business is also going
with us coming to your question
on the health renewal uh percentages uh
that number is that it ranges between 75
to 80 that's the kind of attention that
we get to see your other point on what
kind of street do we see in so far as
the last ratios on the new portfolio and
the older portfolio on the new I think
the portfolio of ratio could range again
anywhere between 45 to 50 and the old
portfolio loss ratios could range
between 75 to 80.
got it so someone last question uh yeah
um
the next question is from the lineup
from mirabiles please go ahead uh yeah
hi thanks so I have three questions
first is that 48 of the gdpi comes from
broker Channel I think uh couldn't find
anything about number of Brokers or how
has been the growth uh on the broker
front so can you talk about that
and also do we have a separate
tablespoon
yeah so there are two two segments of
business where Brokers one is the motor
business all the oems uh that MISD
business largely comes through Brokers
this could be an oem controller OEM
broker like maruti has their own broking
entity through which you you get access
to the dealerships uh or some of the uh
oems work with other Brokers but it's
still a broking business uh you know in
terms of the business coming through and
how we're reflecting our numbers so one
is the modern business which is a OEM
driven MIT business so that's one the
second is the corporate business uh
corporate you know we one of the few
companies which has a direct sales team
so we have direct relationship
management teams which does Business
Development goes to corporates but we
are equally work with Brokers uh
particularly from the sne segment and
also for uh corporate uh corporate
customers now for the SME and for
corporate customers we have a separate
working which is very currently looking
at the working Channel
thank you
ladies and gentlemen due to time
constraint we take that as the last
question I now have the conference over
to Mr bhargav Das Gupta for closing
comments over to you sir
thank you guys for staying up to listen
to us and let me wish you a wish all of
you a very Happy Diwali on the behalf of
the entire management team of Isis
number thank you and look forward to
interactions all interactions over the
over the Border thank you so much thank
you ladies and gentlemen on behalf of
ICICI Lombard General Insurance Company
Limited that concludes this conference
we thank you all for joining us and you
may now disconnect your lines